

### **ABOUT ME**

Graduated student of UPN "Veteran" Yogyakarta (GPA 3.52) a Full-Stack Website Developer based on Work Experience that keep learning something new, focused on website and core back-end developer. Recently Worked around IT Ecosystem especially in Application Development.

#### **SPECIALIZATION**

#### Go Language

- Gin & Gorm

#### Javascript - Typescript

- VueJS (Front-End)
- NodeJS (Core Back-End)
- Adonis JS (TS Backend Framework)
- ExpressJS (JS Backend Framework)

- Laravel (PHP Framework)
- Codeigniter (PHP Framework)

#### **RDBMS**

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB

#### **DevOps**

- CI/CD Development (GitHub Action)
- Linux Command (Deployment)
- Docker and Kubernetes

### **CERTIFICATION**

- Docker and Kubernetes (Udemy)
- GOLANG Backend Developer (SanberCode)
- DevOps CD/CD Development (BuildWithAngga)
- Fullstack GOLANG-NuxtJS (BuildWithAngga)
- NodeJS BackEnd Developer (Sanbercode)
- VueJS FrontEnd Developer (Sanbercode)
- Information System Analyst (BNSP)
- Belajar Dasar Visualiasi Data (DICODING) - Belajar Machine Learning Pemula (DICODING)
- Android Pemula (DICODING)
- Pemrograman Python (DICODING)

# ADIB BACHTIAR

## WEB DEVELOPER

+6283812146223

adibbachtiar44@gmail.com

in Adib Bachtiar



@xdbchtr

(C) @adbchtr

#### WORK EXPERIENCES

#### Back-End Developer



| March 2022 - Present





- Developing Back-End API for Sistem Akuntansi Proses Retur dan Refund Pembelian Obat (Collection) Dexa Group.
- Developing Back-End API for Sistem Monitoring Anti-Penyuapan (SMAP) PT. Jasa Marga, Tbk
- Developing Migration System and API Aggregator data PT. Jasa Marga, Tbk
- Developing JM-CLICK as Centralized Employee Data

#### Back-End Developer

## **Sanbercode** | July 2021 - March 2022

- Developing Back-End API for Sistem Parkir DKI Jakarta
- Developing Back-End API for Sistem Uji Emisi DKI Jakarta
- Developing Back-End API for membership parking App DKI
- Developing Full-Stack Application for data center FMIPA ITB
- Creating Documentation for Tested Apps

## Full-Stack Developer



| January 2020 - February 2020

• Developing the samudera project logistic system (SPLS)

## **EDUCATION**

UPN "Veteran" Yogyakarta

GPA: 3.52



Informatics Engineering | Aug 2017 - Dec 2021

WHAT'S NEXT? ▶▶

Portfolios & Projects, Achievements



# ADIB BACHTIAR

## WEB DEVELOPER

+6283812146223

adibbachtiar44@gmail.com

in Adib Bachtiar

@xdbchtr

@adbchtr

## PORTFOLIOS AND PROJECTS

ShipIT Clothing Store API

Aplikasi Jual - Beli Pakaian | October 2021 - Present

https://documenter.getpostman.com/view/18083262/UVRAHSAU

#### Specification:

- AdonisJS ( NodeJS TypeScript Core Back-End Framework )
- Secure Payment Gateway with Midtrans
- Secure Authentication with Adonis Authentication Token
- One Time Password (OTP) send Email for Register Account
- Secure Cart System
- Social Authentication (Login with Google, Github)
- Rajaongkir cek ongkir

#### CrowdFunding Apps API

Aplikasi crowdfunding / penggalangan dana | Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

#### https://documenter.getpostman.com/view/18083262/UVC3n9M9

#### Specification:

- GIN & GORM ( GOLANG HTTP Back-End Framework )
- Secure Payment Gateway with Midtrans
- Secure Authentication with JSON Web Token (JWT)
- Secure Cart System

## Sport venue API

Aplikasi booking venue olahraga | May 2021 - June 2021

## https://venues-olahraga.herokuapp.com/docs/index.html

## Specification:

- AdonisJS ( NodeJS TypeScript Core Back-End Framework )
- Secure Authentication with Adonis Authentication Token

#### Website for News API

Aplikasi Berita | March 2021 - April 2021

#### https://raw-team.netlify.app/

#### Specification:

- VueJS ( NodeJS JavaScript Front-End Framework )

#### Edu Of Lite Research Website

Website International Research | Nov 2020 - January 2021

#### https://www.eduoflite.com/

- Codelgniter PHP Framework (Old) - VueJS NextJS (Now)

## Realtime Face Mask Detection

Aplikasi Deteksi Penggunaan Masker | Mar 2021 - Dec 2021

#### Specification:

- Python OPENCV Framework
- YOLOv3 Algorythm

#### SQQRL Clothing Store Website

Website Jual Beli Pakaian | Mar 2020 - May 2020

#### https://www.sqqrl.com/

#### Specification:

- Codelgniter PHP Framework
- secure authentication with hashed password
- Rajaongkir cek ongkir
- email notification for checkout

#### Erista Garden Website

Website Taman dan Rekreasi | Jan 2022 - March

#### https://www.eristagarden.com/

#### Specification:

- Adonjis JS Framework
- secure authentication with hashed password

#### **ACHIEVEMENT**

- 2nd winner of PERMITECH "PERMIKOMNAS TECH EXPO" Juara 2 Nasional Al
- Certified as Master from Sanbercode at GOLANG Backend Bootcamp 2022
- Certified as Master from Sanbercode at VueJS Frontend Bootcamp 2021
- Certified as Master from Sanbercode at NodeJS AdonisJS Backend Bootcamp 2021
- Awardee as the best Student Sanbecode Bootcamp GOLANG 2022
- Awardee as the best final Project GOLANG sanbercode Bootcamp Batch-32
- Awardee as the best final Project VueJS Sanbercode Bootcamp Batch-24
- Awardee as the most Active student Sanbercode Bootcamp Batch-25
- 1st Winner of English Debate SMAN 1 Kab. Tangerang
- 2nd Winner of English Debate SMAN 1 Kab.Tangerang (2015)
- 3rd Winner of English Debate SMAN 1 Kab.Tangerang (2014)

**◄** WHAT'S PREVIOUS ?

Profile, Work Experiences & Certifications